Chapterestablishers
Grudged Kocher
Treasure MUS shooter
üpunderted
Explozu
...
The sunset was even more beautiful than I remembered.
Next thing I knew, I was standing with a hoe in my hand.
That's when I realized I was dreaming.
It was a feeling I knew well, so I got right to work.
Someone's calling me.
Oh, it's my girlfriend.
We broke up five years ago.
Now I see.
In this dream, we never broke up.
Oh, so in this world, I never made it as a pro and decided to return home.
All the lights are on.
I feel like I could cry.
Everyone's here and doing well.
My grandma and grandpa, I miss them so much.
Wow, Kai's incredibly good.
No one here even stands a chance against him.
He's great, isn't he?
Father, grandpa, everyone, I have to apologize.
You've been cheering me on and have had so much faith in me.
It's alright.
Really, you may not have made it as a pro, but you can still be happy.
No matter what path you choose, you can find contentment.
As long as you live each day to the fullest without looking back, we'll always be proud of you.
You'll be fine, Kai.
The funny thing is, even in my dreams, I can't stop playing Shogi.
I also regretted not going pro.
It's no surprise that the whole ordeal made my stomach hurt.
I feel bad for Shimada 8th Dan.
This whole thing must be like a nightmare.
Yeah, he's dead in the water.
And with four straight losses, he won't get to have a match in his hometown.
If you can't say anything nice, don't say anything at all.
If only that were the case, but I won't expect an apology anytime soon.
Oh, my damn stomach.
Alright then, I guess it's time to get ready.
The Mii who couldn't become a pro and moved back to the countryside.
The Mii who risked it all to make it this far, only to face four straight losses.
Which is the true nightmare?
Let's find out by seeing it through to the end.
The Shishio Tournament. Match 4, Day 2.
Yesterday, Meijin Soya secured his defense and then launched the first attack.
But Mr. Shimada countered. He's in the lead, but not by much.
Knight to 7-3. Just as Mr. Shimada started to attack, the game was adjourned.
Don't you think Mr. Shimada is using his Knight to 7-3 a little too soon?
Yeah, I think you're right. It just feels like he's panicking instead of really thinking about his attacks.
Would you like some miso soup?
No, sorry. Yeah, sure.
It's like he doesn't want to draw it out. And he does look kinda sick, even if that's the case.
Shimada's doing the best he can, but I doubt he'll win.
Well, not against Soya anyway.
We're probably looking at four straight losses.
He's gonna miss another chance at a showdown in his hometown. Yamagata's a long way off.
Almost everyone seems to be thinking the same thing.
They're all ready to declare Soya the winner.
And sure, Mr. Shimada has been aggressive this match.
But I wouldn't say he's panicking. He's playing like normal.
At least that's how it looks to me.
The battle of nerves continues.
Mr. Shimada, fearless in the face of Meijin Soya, was able to earn a few points.
It's not as bad as they think.
Huh?
Kiriyama?
Why didn't you tell me, Mr. Shimada?
Kibata wasn't feeling well!
I would have taken him to Kyoto in a limo with a bed!
Shimada wasn't feeling well.
I would have taken him to Kyoto in a limo with a bed.
I know what you're doing.
You've been practicing together behind my back.
So why'd you leave me out?
Don't forget that he's my coach and I've been a part of his workshop way longer than you have.
You got it?
Sorry about that, Nikaido.
I was going to call you sooner, but I haven't had the chance.
And, uh, Mr. Shimada is... well...
Please, don't.
He'll just make a big fuss.
The stress from that alone would make a hole in my stomach.
So please, don't tell Nikaido.
Mr. Shimada, are you okay? I'll be there as soon as I can!
One time, he was so worried that he landed his helicopter in the courtyard of the neighborhood elementary school.
I would have flown to him this time if I didn't have a match.
Kiriyama, take care of him.
Stay with him, even after the match is over.
Knowing him, no matter what happens, I know he'll play to the very end.
Yeah, got it.
I'll make sure to keep an eye on him.
I'll bring him home.
Chairman, please, let me do the morning broadcast.
At least let me re-assure the match.
I'm fine. I can do this.
I can do it!
I wore a new kimono just for the occasion.
Let me be on TV!
Tsuji Ninth Den.
He's the official observer.
He has the flu.
They just found out and he wouldn't leave.
Everybody, gargle and wash your hands!
Does anyone else have the flu?
I need to know!
If any of you infect the players, I'll kill you myself!
That guy!
He's been clearing his throat since yesterday morning, but I thought maybe he was just being
snobby.
I can't believe he'd want to be on TV so badly that he'd cover up having the flu.
I know.
It's too bad.
He's handsome enough for TV.
Talk about a waste of good looks.
I'm promoting you, Smith.
Your time as an assistant observer is over.
You're now the official observer.
What?
So suddenly?
It starts in ten minutes.
All right.
Head to the match room.
Wait.
I have to open the sealed move envelope?
That's way too important on my first day.
Let's get started.
Not to mention, I'm an observer for someone else's title match before I have my own.
This is terrible.
It's a bad omen.
It's going to be fine.
Don't worry.
Hardly any of the professional players here have had a title match.
It's very rare.
Except for me.
I've had a few.
I'm opening the envelope of another player's sealed move before I get to use one.
It's kind of like signing off as a witness on a friend's marriage license before getting
married myself.
You know?
But even still, it is a great honor.
And now, here's the envelope.
The sealed move.
Silver to 6-6.
And then, the curtain calmly rose on the second day.
Wait a minute.
What about...
Oh, hey!
Kiriyama!
And so, I would like to begin with an explanation of the demonstration board for this second day
of the fourth match of the 20th Shishio Tournament.
First of all, the demonstration board commentator will be...
Kiryu Champion, Raido Fujimoto!
Since the observer of this match, Suji Ninth Den has the flu, we had to act fast and ask
Rei Kiriyama Fifth Den to replace him as co-commentator on the demonstration board.
We hope you enjoy the proceedings.
Anything you'd like to add?
Nice to meet you all.
I'll do my best.
As you may know, Kiriyama Fifth Den is known for becoming only the fifth professional shogi
player to get his start in middle school.
The other four that were middle school pros, including Meijin Soya, all went on to become
grandmasters themselves.
Some even say middle school pros are future grandmasters.
Do you think you'll be following in their footsteps?
Well, for me, my older colleagues were much more skilled.
I'm actually pretty small in comparison.
Sorry.
Ah, come on.
It doesn't matter if he was a middle school student when he made his debut, not when he
suddenly got stuck after reaching C1.
Well, as a first year high school student, I made my debut, but I was at B2.
So what I'm really trying to say is...
I'm more impressive!
That's my point!
And while we're at it, why is the world so enamored with the expression middle school
debut?
It's baffling to me!
Future grandmaster?
A grandmaster?
Nobody knows that for sure!
For sure!
The goal of becoming a pro is all well and good.
But if your goal isn't becoming a grandmaster at all costs, why are you even playing Shogi?
It can be assumed that having no desire is a rather beautiful thing, but it doesn't make any sense
that a goal is good and yet a desire is bad.
Aren't they the same exact thing?
Yeah!
That desire is obvious.
Our mystical matey has hindered my every move, but I swear I'll drag him off that throne
and become grandmaster myself!
Yeah, yeah!
Until that happens, you can bet that I won't drop from A rank!
In fact, once I'm matey, I'll hold on to the title till I die!
Ha ha!
That's all!
Wow, Mr. Shimada, you were surrounded by people like this and fought them on a daily basis?
The fact that you only suffer from stomach aches makes you just as monstrous as they are!
I can't do it!
Class A is too crazy!
AAAAAAAAAAAAAH!!!
It hurts...
...it hurts
Son of a bitch. I swear. Damn it. It's like a dark swamp. Dropping. Churning. In the pit of my stomach.
All this pain just makes me feel alive.
Oh. He's going with pawn to 5-7 promoted? That's crazy. If he lets up on the attack, he'll be surrounded.
His king's on pretty shaky ground. How long can he keep up the attack?
Silver to 6-7. Threatmate. Silver to 7-8. Rook to 2-8. Threatmate again.
Can Shimada finish him off like this? Still, his opponent is Soya.
Yeah, but can he win? Not a chance.
Rook to 7-1.
He wrote it out. Using just a rook and a pawn.
And now, it's Soya's turn.
That was it. Where Shimada Eifdan's attack stopped.
And Meijin Soya's counterattack began.
That's the game.
I'm out of here.
Snow.
No matter how I struggle,
it'll bury me mercilessly.
It's a blinding darkness.
It's almost too much.
So silent.
It's overwhelming.
It's captivatingly beautiful.
Oh, such beauty.
Wait.
Please, wait.
Don't go.
It's not over yet.
Huh?
His fortress was torn down.
His king's in danger.
And his opponent, Soya.
There's no way he can turn it around from here.
But still, it's not over yet.
His pieces are still in play, so it's not over.
It is over.
Shimada's done, kid.
It's not like he stood a chance in the first place.
Four straight losses.
He's a stubborn weakling.
What?
Aren't you in that shogi workshop Shimada put together?
I understand not wanting to admit your mentor's in trouble,
but you're affecting his reputation.
So keep your mouth shut.
Well, Shimada then did his best.
Yeah.
Fine, if you consider who his opponent was.
He can't be helped.
He was outclassed.
Well, it was Soya, after all.
Four straight losses.
Yeah, but even still, he could have won once.
I wanted to see some backbone.
He didn't show us anything.
I'm not surprised.
Yamagato was a long way off.
Well, what did you expect?
No.
No, that's wrong.
This board doesn't look dead.
Not to me, anyway.
I don't think that...
Mr. Shimada's pieces...
are dead.
They're alive.
To me.
Uh, Kiriyama?
Wait!
Where are you going?
Kiriyama 5th then!
Mr. Shimada...
Wait!
Don't give up!
Mr. Fujimoto!
No!
Mr. Shimada...
Shimada, Ethan, conceded.
Like I said, he never stood a chance.
I tried to warn you.
So it went unnoticed, huh?
This darkness isn't just playing on an endless loop.
Hey, wait!
This is...
Seven-Nine-Bishop.
It's a reversal?
The two-four-night's threatmate is gone, too.
Huh?
Isn't Mei-jin-soya's king under check?
And then...
With just one move...
The world...
Reveals a completely different form.
A small opening at the end.
A tiny gap.
A spark of light shining through.
Oh, well.
You had too much faith in me.
And it was beautiful, too.
And so, the Shishio Tournament ended with Mr. Shimada's four consecutive losses.
That night, Mr. Shimada and I left Kyoto for the journey home.
I have some water and a light meal.
As I watched him lying there, pale and exhausted, I thought about the path he had taken.
That's right.
I knew it from the start.
The truth.
What lies beyond the other side of the storm.
It's just...
Another...
Even more furious storm.
No matter how many times you fall, you have to pick up the pieces and move on.
In this world, you must find a way to keep moving forward.
Wandering without end.
Then why?
The answer to that, isn't something someone else can give you.
The only way to know that, is by asking yourself, in the middle of that raging storm.
No matter where I go, the rain always follows me around.
Just go and have a good time. Relax, the fresh air will do you good.
Well, things have settled down here, but I guess Sis likes it like this.
It looks like I've lost.
Thank you very much, everyone.
I can't believe I had to reveal the sealed move.
Don't miss the next march comes in like a lion.
Strawberry, I'm coming home!
I'm coming home!